# Nikhil kumar K

#### CONTACT

nikhilk00821@gmail.com 9600057219

#### **SUMMARY**

Been working at Cognizant for the past two years as a front-end developer. Worked on three web applications and gained good knowledge on web development. Well versed with front-end frameworks - **Angular** and **React**. An excellent problem solver.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Pvt. Ltd.,

28th Jun 2016 — Present

Programmer Analyst

- Worked on "FDA", a web application of client Novartis, from November, 2017 to April, 2018. Technology stack was ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS and SQL Server. Part of Front-end development team. Involved in Back-end development as well.
- Worked on "DIANE", a web application of client Societe Generale, from September, 2017 to November, 2017. Technology stack was Angular 5.2.5 and Spring. Part of Front-end development team.
- Worked on "BIA Tool", a web application of client Societe Generale, from January, 2017 to August, 2017. Technology stack was AngularJS and Spring. Part of Front-end development team.
- Worked on "Ekart", awebapplication, as part of MFRP at Cognizant. Technology stack was AngularJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS and MongoDB (MEAN Stack). It got selected as the best project of the batch.

## **EDUCATION**

B. Tech. in CSE Aug 2012 — May 2016

SRM University, Kattankulathur

Secured 8.2 CGPA out of 10.

12th Standard Jun 2010 — Mar 2011

Narayana Junior College, Hyderabad

Secured 91.1% of marks in state board's exams (11th and 12th combined).

10th Standard Jun 2008 — Apr 2009

Bhashyam High School, Hyderabad

Secured 93.2% of marks in state board's exams.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frameworks: Angular 5, ReactJS, AngularJS and Redux.
- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, ES 6, OOJS and TypeScript.
- **Web Design:** HTML 5, CSS 3, Responsive Web Design and Bootstrap 3.
- CSS Pre-processors: LESS and SASS.
- **Backend Frameworks:** NodeJS and ExpressJS.
- **Databases:** MongoDB and SQL Server.

Nikhil kumar K

- **Unit Testing:** Jasmine, Karma and Protractor.
- Tools: Git, Angular CLI, Webpack, Babel, and Gulp.
- C, C++ and SQL.

#### **ACCOLADES**

- Awarded with monthly AVM Sparkle Award June'17 for contributions towards BIA Tool application.
- Been appreciated by leads and project managers for keeping up with the deadlines.
- Received many appreciation emails from the client.

#### PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Have sound communication skills.
- Able to work under pressure.
- Quick at learning new technologies.

### CO CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Completed B. Tech. final year project titled, "Delay-optimized File Retrieval using LT-based cloud storage".
- Participated in "Big Data Analytics" workshop organized by C-DAC at SRM University during Aaruush'14 and have got trained on Hadoop Eco System Tools.
- Attended "Ethical Hacking Expert (Integrated Level 1.0 & 2.0)", a two-day workshop conducted by TechDefence at SRM University during Aaruush'14.
- Participated in "Parallel Programming Basics", a one-day workshop conducted by Calligo Technologies and have gained knowledge in High Performance Computing (HPC).
- Underwent an Inplant Training on "C++ and Java" from Cognizance Professional Solutions LLP, Chennai.

#### EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in various social activities conducted by "Outreach" of Cognizant.
- Volunteered several roadshows and fests in Cognizant.
- A member of NSS club during under graduation.

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

■ **Date of Birth:** 26-12-1993

■ **Gender:** Male

■ Passport Status: Active

I hereby declare that the above information furnished by me is true to the best of my knowledge.

Nikhil kumar K

11-06-2018

Nikhil kumar K